Tahim M. Kader

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tahimkader | Email: tahim.kader@gmail.com | Github: github.com/tkaderr | Personal: tahimk.com | Cell: 408-427-7500

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced business and technology professional with almost 5 years of demonstrated experience in product management, software development, and data analytics. Detailed oriented, quick, learner, excellent communicator, and efficient in time management. Recently completed an intensive coding boot camp with over 1000 hours of experience in mobile and full stack development. Currently looking for opportunities as a mobile or web developer.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley, Bachelor of Science, Bioengineering 2012

Certificate of Completion, Coding Dojo, 2017

• An immersive web and mobile development boot camp that focused on front-end fundamentals and three full stacks: Python, MEAN, and Swift. Earned over 1000 hours of coding experience, including the ability to deploy mobile and full websites from client to server to database

TECHNICAL SKILL SETS

- Languages: JavaScript, Swift, Python, SQL, C, MATLAB, Perl
- Front End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Angular, React, Redux
- Back End: Django, Flask, Node.js, Express.js, Socket.IO, REST
- Databases: MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Development Tools: Visual Studio, Atom, XCode, Heroku, SQLWorkbench, AWS
- Other Tools: Balsamiq, Google Analytics, Looker, Woopra, Iterable, Microsoft Office

PROJECTS

Super Asteroid Frenzy https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1244314875>

- Super Asteroid Frenzy is an IOS mobile game where the user controls a spaceship that shoots on-coming asteroids
- Created whole application from start to finish
- Technologies: Swift, Spritekit, XCode, AVFoundation

Color Frenzy <github.com/tkaderr/color_frenzy >

- Color Frenzy is an IOS application built in 24 hours where the user tries to match a color by rotating the device in X, Y, Z axis
- Collaborated and led initiative on the CoreMotion logic and code for the game
- Technologies: Swift, CoreMotion, XCode, AudioToolbox, AVFoundation

Rental App < our-things.herokuapp.com >

- Rental App is a web application that allows users to post and rent products
- Created the user dashboard that showed all user's posted products and products being rented
- Technologies: Python, Django, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQLite

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Product Manager - Dot&Bo

January 2016 - September 2016

- Led User Acceptance Testing to ensure all new product functionality have been created as designed on time; measured performance against custom-made product requirement documents for new Storefront by working closely with Engineering Team
- Improved customer and internal user experience by researching data, gathered requirements, creating Product Requirement Documents, including specifications on new website functionality, and designing Wireframes using Balsamiq tool for desktop and mobile experience
- Led and collaborated with Engineering team on sprint planning to assure that prioritized product features, which was based on the product roadmap, would be completed on time within two week cycle periods through agile methodology
- Tested and measured performance on various email campaigns by A/B testing to see which types of email strategies were more effective to the
 customer and deployed those respective campaigns to bring in thousands of dollars more in revenue

Lead Data Analyst - Dot&Bo

August 2015 - January 2016

- Collaborated with management and key internal stakeholders to create and maintain KPI dashboards for the Content, Finance, Operations/Vendor Management, and Marketing teams using business intelligence tool, Looker
- Performed numerous product pricing and shipping optimization model analysis for the merchandising team by looking at historical purchase data, during the holidays to boost customer purchases and revenue
- Created with VP Merchandising/ Co-founder a methodology for "Best Selling Products" based on key metrics for our top 15 categories on our
 website; this new organization helped physical product placement on website to better market strong performing products and boost revenue

Senior Data Business Analyst - Accenture

May 2014 - May 2015

- Completed necessary client board design documents for new release of the COTS product successfully by attending client board meetings and gathering requirements from the client
- Improved system testing, product testing processes, and helped develop maintenance schedules by collaborating closely with manager and test lead on associated tasks
- Generated SQL queries, Excel, and Word documents to update the product test deliverable by working with test lead; updates were successfully
 used for the offshore test team